A hash function is a function that converts that data it's given into an irregular value of text size,
a hash function might be easier to understand if we imagine as it is a blender when we input data into
a hash function like ABC, its output and irregular value.
If we imagine a hash function as a machine that blends up data, it's easier to understand.
So the regular output from a hash is called a hash value.
Hash values are numbers but are often written in hexadecimal.
Computers manage all data in binary, which uses zeros and ones.
Hash values are also data and are managed and by.
What a hash function is actually doing is performing some value calculations inside the computer.
Let's look at some features of hash functions from this premise.
Their first characteristic is characteristic is that the data values they output are fixed size and
fixed length.
The length of their output data varies according to the hash function.
In this case of such a Dash one, for example, it's fixed at 20 bytes.
We will see the different types of hashing later on, even when we went extremely large.
Amounts of data are input output.
Hash data does not do that in length.
It's still 20, so we have this hash going.
The amount of data does not is not related to the hash value length.
Likewise, no matter how small the input, the length of the hash value data is the same.
So if we put one letter, it will become will give us the same length.
A second characteristic is that if given the same input, they will will invariably produce the same
out ABC, ABC.
We will give.
We will get the same hashing, okay, and the same output, a third characteristic, if that if similar
data is even different by one, by a bit their output, their output greatly differs.
So if I have a B C and a b d, we will get completely different hash.
OK.
It is not the case that if similar data is input, the hash values will be the similar to the first
characteristic is that if even if completely different data is input, it does happen that an identical
hash values are produced and low.
The chances may be so if I have here and a file.
It may produce.
The same hash.
A hash function.
Again, as if it is a function that converts the data into a given area, it's given into an irregular
value of fixed size.
Just remembering the fifth characteristics of this hash function is that converting hash values back
into their original data is, in reality, impossible.
So I can't get back the date that this is the hash value.
I can't get it back with ABC.
The flow of input and output is one way, which is a big difference from the encryption.
So the encryption you can get the encryption and decryption while hashing, only converting that data
into hash values.
One final characteristic that can be given is that their calculations are relatively simple.
Consider ABC.
This is the hash value, and it will give us like this value.
There are a number of hash function at algorithm, but currently it is most common to use as a dash
to.
We have MD5, and before such a zero, a one and a two hash function functions can be used to output
a summary of that data input and are used in many situations.
Examples of hash functions usage are explained in detail and the like message authentication, codes
and hash tables, and the following exercises and lessons.